<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[csfam]]></title>
  <link href="http://csfam.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://csfam.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-23T01:06:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://csfam.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[csfam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring Heroku's concurrent request performance for long-running requests]]></title>
    <link href="http://csfam.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/measuring-herokus-concurrent-request-performance/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://csfam.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/measuring-herokus-concurrent-request-performance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been meaning to write some posts here for a while, and I&#8217;m glad I&#8217;m finally getting around to it. The first thing I wanted to write about is some testing we did a couple months back with the number of concurrent user requests that could be handled by <a href="http://www.heroku.com">Heroku</a> using a variety of backend technologies. But first off, in case you&#8217;ve managed to miss it &#8211; what is Heroku, why are we using it, and how does it work?</p>

<ul>
<li>It is a cloud-based application platform with built-in scalability and management tools.</li>
<li>It makes things dead simple from deployment to scaling up.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s free as long as you stay under a monthly traffic limit, which is perfect if you&#8217;re just starting up your idea.</li>
<li>Essentially dynos handle web requests within the Heroku architecture, and scaling up your application is just a matter of increasing the number of dynos you are using. Piece of cake.</li>
</ul>


<p>One of the other nice things about Heroku is it provides developers with a good amount of freedom in terms of what languages and frameworks can be used. Heroku will support JVM-based languages (Java, Scala, etc.), Ruby, Node.js, and Python. We were considering a number of options for the language and framework to use for our latest project, <a href="http://demo.udunit.com">udunit</a>, and we had narrowed our list down to <a href="http://scala-lang.org">Scala</a> and the <a href="http://liftweb.net/">Lift framework</a>, <a href="http://www.python.org">Python</a> and the <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django framework</a>, or <a href="http://nodejs.org">Node.js</a> and the <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express framework</a>.</p>

<h2>The Tests</h2>

<p>We set up very simple Heroku projects &#8211; one for each of the three frameworks mentioned above &#8211; that would result in a long-running request (i.e. the server was &#8220;busy&#8221; generating the response for ~2 seconds). Using the <a href="http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.4/programs/ab.html">Apache Bench</a> tool, we were able to do some load testing of the various frameworks running on Heroku. What we really wanted to test was how well a single Heroku dyno would handle concurrent requests. So we ran tests via Apache Bench with increasingly more concurrent requests: 1, 2, 3, 4,5, 10, 20. The tests each hit a page which would trigger a long-running request. The tests were executed with a command like</p>

<pre><code> ab -n 200 -c 20
</code></pre>

<p>for 200 total requests with 20 requests at a time. Apache Bench provides data on the requests sent, such as the average number of requests handled per second (see graph below) or the min/max time taken to handle a single request. Using this data we were able to get an idea of what one Heroku dyno could handle.</p>

<h2>The Results</h2>

<p>Here we have a chart showing the number of requests handled per second for each of the three frameworks. Everyone was able to keep up while the number of concurrent requests was small; at 5 concurrent requests, all the frameworks were handling ~2.5 requests per second &#8211; so pretty close to ideal (5 requests / 2 second long-running request = 2.5 requests per second).</p>

<script type="text/javascript" src="http://csfam.github.com//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/static/modules/gviz/1.0/chart.js"> {"dataSourceUrl":"//docs.google.com/spreadsheet/tq?key=0AlrawxK1noHLdExqRUhLWFp6YXkwaFVyOENseE1TZkE&transpose=0&headers=1&merge=COLS&range=B2%3AB9%2CH2%3AH9%2CH14%3AH21%2CH26%3AH33%2CI2%3AI9&gid=0&pub=1","options":{"vAxes":[{"title":"requests per second handled","minValue":null,"viewWindowMode":"pretty","viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},{"viewWindowMode":"pretty","viewWindow":{}}],"series":{"1":{"color":"#109618"},"3":{"color":"#dc3912"}},"booleanRole":"certainty","title":"Concurrent requests handled via Heroku","animation":{"duration":500},"vAxis":{"format":""},"useFirstColumnAsDomain":true,"hAxis":{"title":"concurrent requests","format":""},"isStacked":false,"width":600,"height":371},"state":{},"view":{"columns":[{"calc":"stringify","type":"string","sourceColumn":0},1,2,3,4]},"chartType":"ColumnChart","chartName":"Chart 1"} </script>


<p>When the load started getting higher, performance began dropping off (mainly in the python-django setup, somewhat in the scala-lift setup, hardly at all for node.js and express). Moving up to 50 concurrent requests, both Django and Lift became hardly useable, though surprisingly Express maintained a very high level of performance. Node.js and Express were the clear winners here, though it should be noted that we were going with the default configuration for Lift and Django. With better tuning of the server configuration, we could probably get higher performance from these two frameworks.</p>

<p>In the end we decided to go with the Lift framework. It&#8217;s performance was still strong and increasing system responsiveness while under high load is just a matter of increasing the number of Heroku dynos being used. Lift also provides a much fuller and more powerful framework than Express does. In the end Lift&#8217;s strong performance and rich set of features won us over. But I&#8217;m definitely going to push for some Node.js projects in the future ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[in the beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://csfam.github.com/blog/2012/01/05/in-the-beginning/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T23:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://csfam.github.com/blog/2012/01/05/in-the-beginning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There was this group of people, who got to know each other in the basement of a computer lab.  They were a talented bunch, during their time in the lab they built interesting projects and had fun working with each other.  They made a good team.  Then the good times were over and they had to graduate.  They all went their separate ways, but many of them later, during cold rainy nights sitting in front of computers in cubicles working on other people&#8217;s work, would remember those good times and wish they could be part of something like that sometime again.</p>

<p>Many years later, they get laid-off from their jobs at the big corporations to be replaced by new dream-filled youth &#8211; youth just as ready to give up their dreams, creativity and energy in exchange for job security.   As they leave the building and watch the new hires take their places they wonder if it could have been different.</p>

<p>…</p>

<p>Wait a sec!  It can be different!  We are all talented, energetic, and good at what we do!  We are creative.  We love applying ourselves to new projects.  There is no reason not to harness this power!  We are powerful!  We love cs and graphics and making things.  We are scientists and inventors, artists and artisans, and we are funny and fun.  We play flash games and we waste time on tv shows, and we create and deliver.</p>

<p>CSFAM &#8211; is the chance for all of us to do what we want, what we&#8217;re interested in, to create the work that we love with the people we love working with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
